In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to pronounce the G and K consonant sounds.
我们将学习如何发音G和K辅音。
These two sounds are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
这两个音被放在一起是因为它们的口腔位置相同。
Kk is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth,
Kk是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔，
and gg is voiced,
而gg是有声的，
meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
意味着你用声带发出声音。
Gg.
Gg。
These consonants are stop consonants,
这些辅音是爆破音，
which means there are two parts to each sound.
这意味着每个音都有两个部分。
First,
首先，
a stop in the air flow,
气流的阻断，
and second, a release.
然后是释放。
We stop the flow of air here,
我们在这里阻断气流，
closing our vocal cords, while the back part of the tongue reaches up to touch the soft palate.
闭合声带，同时舌头的后部上升触碰软腭。
I'm going to slow down the K sound in the word back.
我将放慢单词back中的K音。
See if you can hear the stop of air before the release.
看看你能否听到释放前的气流阻断。
Back.
Back。
Kk.
Kk。
Back.
Back。
Here you can see the tongue position.
这里你可以看到舌头的位置。
The back of the tongue reaches up to touch the soft palate,
舌头的后部上升触碰软腭，
which is closed.
这是闭合的。
The tip of the tongue can remain forward,
舌尖可以保持在前面，
lightly touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
轻轻触碰下前牙的后面。
The jaw drops a little bit,
下巴稍微下垂，
and the lips are open.
嘴唇是张开的。
Kk.
Kk。
Gg.
Gg。
The lip position doesn't matter for these sounds,
这些音的嘴唇位置并不重要，
so the lips might start forming the next sound,
所以嘴唇可能开始形成下一个音，
like in the word great.
比如在单词great中。
Here,
在这里，
the lips can start taking the position for the R as we make the G.
当我们发G音时，嘴唇可以开始为R音做准备。
Gg.
Gg。
Great.
Great。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些音。
The jaw drops and the back of the tongue lifts to touch the soft palate.
下巴下垂，舌头的后部抬起触碰软腭。
Then the tongue releases.
然后舌头释放。
Sometimes, to make a sentence smoother,
有时，为了使句子更流畅，
the words more linked together,
单词之间更连贯，
native speakers will skip the release of a stop consonant when the next word begins with a consonant.
母语者会在下一个单词以辅音开头时省略爆破音的释放。
For example,
例如，
the phrase back to work.
短语back to work。
Back to.
Back to。
I'm not saying back to.
我并没有说back to。
Kk.
Kk。
With the full release of the K.
完整释放K音。
I'm holding the air for a fraction of a second with my throat,
我用喉咙短暂地阻止空气，
making that stop, then I go right into the release of the T consonant.
形成那个阻断，然后直接进入T辅音的释放。
Back to.
Back to。
Back to work.
Back to work。
Without the release of the K in back,
在back中没有释放K音，
the two words flow together more easily, making it smoother.
两个单词更容易流畅地连在一起，使其更顺畅。
Notice I do make a light release of the K in the word work.
注意我在单词work中确实轻轻释放了K音。
Can you hear it?
你能听到吗？
Back to work.
Back to work。
Let's look at some words up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察一些单词。
Word keep.
单词keep。
Because the tongue lifts at the back and does not require much jaw drop,
因为舌头在后部抬起，不需要太多下巴下垂，
it's hard to see this sound in this word.
在这个单词中很难看到这个音。
The word green.
单词green。
The lips round for the G because they need to round for the next sound, R.
嘴唇为G音圆起，因为它们需要为下一个音R圆起。
The lip position doesn't change the G sound.
嘴唇位置不会改变G音。
It's a little easier to see the back of the tongue move when it's at the end of a word like this word.
当它在单词末尾时，舌头后部的移动更容易看到，比如这个单词。
Egg.
Egg。
The tongue lifts in the back, then releases.
舌头在后部抬起，然后释放。
The G and K consonants.
G和K辅音。
Keep.
Keep。
Green.
Green。
Egg.
Egg。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Go.
Go。
G.
G。
Go.
Go。
Again.
Again。
G.
G。
Again.
Again。
Big.
Big。
G.
G。
Big.
Big。
Cry.
Cry。
K.
K。
Cry.
Cry。
Key.
Key。
K.
K。
Key.
Key。
Black.
Black。
K.
K。
Black.
Black。